

Chatham, NJ

+1 (908) 642-6883

ATKincaid74@gmail.com

andrew-kincaid.com

github.com/atkincaid74

in LinkedIn.com/in/a-t-kin

SUMMARY

Quantitative Analyst by title, full-stack developer by trade. 4+ years developing a full-stack web application from the ground up, with ownership of the python package responsible for all insurance-related models. Fast-learner and a team player with a strong work ethic. Passionate about using my problem-solving skills to find creative solutions. Dedicated to writing clean, well-tested code.

SKILLS

- ★ Advanced ★ Intermediate ☆ Familiar LANGUAGES
- ★ Python | ★ JavaScript | ★ HTML/CSS | ★ Bash FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES
- ★ Django | ★ Vue.is | ☆ Flask
- ★ Pandas/NumPy | ★ SQLAlchemy | ☆ Scikit-learn OPERATING SYSTEMS
- ★ Windows | ★ Linux (RHEL/Ubuntu)

EXPERIENCE

12/2019 - present **Quantitative Analyst II**

AM Best Company

- Built and maintained the analytical Python package for the Quantitative Analysis Team, including a capital adequacy model, projection model, and other credit rating tools; reviewed the code for all pull requests to the package to ensure the team's standards were met
- Contributed to the Vue.js single page application and Django REST API that allowed internal analysts and external clients to interact with the models
- Designed and implemented the CI/CD solution for team's production application; built Azure DevOps pipelines for testing, linting, building and deploying application
- Communicated directly with the analysts using the application to gather feedback and constantly improve the product before and after its official launch
- Worked closely with the system engineer to deploy the application on Red Hat Enterprise Linux servers

6/2018 - 12/2019 Quantitative Analyst I

AM Best Company

- Created the quantitative analysis group's database schemas and objects. Collaborated with the database administrators to constantly enhance the efficiency of the database
- Acted as the representative for my team of developers to the company's IT department to ensure that goals and timelines were aligned

AM Best Company

- 6 week orientation that gave a strong working knowledge of the insurance sector and an in depth look at rating agencies and their role in the market
- Converted a suite of existing MS Excel/VBA models into Python. Brought 8 separate models into one code base to drastically improve maintainability

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

B.S. - Mathematics, Chemistry minor

Muhlenberg College

- Graduated with Honors in Mathematics and a 3.9 major GPA
- Awarded the Harry A Benfer Memorial Scholarship for "promoting goodwill and demonstrating an appreciation for all phases of college life"

EXAMS & DESIGNATIONS

REFERENCES

 Associate in Insurance Accounting and Finance - The Institutes Available upon request

• Exams P and FM - Society of Actuaries